

Belay Birhanu Gibina

Date of birth: 06/06/1994 | Nationality: Ethiopian | Gender: Male | Phone number:

(+251) 921640816 (Mobile) | Email address: 2belamit@gmail.com | Website: https://github.com/belaymit |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/belay-birhanu-144ba714b/ | **Skype:** 2belamit |

Whatsapp Messenger: +251 92 164 0816 | Address: College District, Bole sub city, 1888, Adama, Ethiopia (Work)

About me:

I am Belay. At the Microverse coding school, I am a full-stack web development student with a keen interest in web frontend development, which includes pair programming and industry-standard projects. In June 2018, I received a BSc in Science with a concentration in Computer Science and Engineering from Mekelle Institute of Technology (MIT). At Haramaya University, where I spent my first three years as an assistant lecturer, I initially taught programming courses. I quit my job because I realized that teaching was not going to be my long-term profession and I wasn't exposed to the competition I had hoped for. Despite not having joined a firm as a developer, I have been learning web development, primarily ReactJS and Redux, for the past five months.

WORK EXPERIENCE

30/10/2018 - CURRENT Haramaya, Ethiopia, Ethiopia

ASSISTANT LECTURER, HARAMAYA UNIVERSITY, ETHIOPIA HARAMAYA UNIVERSITY

- I instructed many students in a variety of courses, including laboratory courses.
- Leading some important portfolios in the department I am working-graduating class students' practical attachments.
- Assisting lecturers in laboratory specifically in courses like Artificial Intelligence, Machine learning, Data Science, Computer Vision and operations research.
- Teaches students how to address problems in different directions
- Maintain computers and similar laboratory resources of the department.

19/10/2022 - CURRENT Remote, Ethiopia

WEB DEVELOPER MICROVERSE CODDING SCHOOL

- Work on industry standard projects every week.
- I am currently enrolled in the second module of the Microverse program.
- The great thing about learning to code at Microverse coding school is that we have been able to solve various problems by debugging every line of code we write. In fact, it is the only company that teaches students how to deal with such specific situations.
- By implementing a solid process that works for developers, testers, and users, I can design responsive, qualified, consistent, and user friendly software.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/10/2014 - 22/06/2018 Mekelle, Ethiopia

BSC. DEGREE CERTIFICATE Mekelle University-Mekelle Institute of Technology(MIT), Ethiopia

- Principles of Computing, Programming in C, Object oriented Programming with C++, Computer Organization & Architecture, Microprocessors. Data Structures, Data Communications, Systems Anal ysis and Design, Database Management Systems.
- Design and Analysis of algorithms, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Computer Graphics, Microprocessor, Advanced Microprocessors, System Simulation & Modelling, Operating System, Compiler Design, Artificial Intelligence & Expert Systems, PC Hardware Troubleshooting Cryptography & Network Security, Neural Networks & Fuzzy Logic.
- Computational Methods, Systems Programming, Micro controllers, Analogue electronics (I & II), Digital electronics (I & II), signals and systems, Digital Signal Processing.

• Engineering Mathematics (I, II & III), Entrepreneurship, Engineering economics and Management and In troduction to economics, Research Method and Presentation, Civics and Ethical Education, Fresh man Physics & Modern Physics.

Address Mekelle. Tigray, Ethiopia, mekelle/15, Mekelle, Ethiopia | Website http://www.mu.edu.et/ |

Field of study Computer Science and Engineering | Final grade 3.83 on scale of 4.0 | Level in EQF EQF level 6 |

Type of credits Credit Hours | Number of credits 174 | Valid until 30/10/2024 |

Thesis Detection and classification of agricultural plant leaf disease using image processing and ConvNet

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **AFAAN OROMO**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C2	C1	C1	C2
AMHARIC	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Operating System and Software Installations | Programming Language | Plugins | Development tools | ReactJS | HTML5/CSS3, SASS, JavaScript (including recent versions) | Databases used: SQL, MySQL, Firebase Realtime Database | Python, Django, Asyncio | Git + Github + Subversion | Redux toolkit | Context API

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

15/10/2016 - 23/06/2018

Final, Mini, Summer and Different Course Projects Detection and classification of Agricultural Plant Leaf diseases using Image Processing and ConvNet, Ultrasonic and GSM based smart stick for visually impaired persons, Android based tourism management and tourism location tracking system in Ethiopia, Hand Written digit recognition (Artificial Neural Network and Fuzzy Logic), Online Patient Appointment Scheduling System (Research method and Presentation)

19/10/2022 - CURRENT

Educational Projects at Microverse

- Portfolio and Capstone Project I HTML, CSS and JavaScript DOM manipulation
- Awesome Books-ES6, Todo-list-ES6, Leaderboard-ES6 HTML, CSS, linter, webpack and ES6 modules
- react-simple-website developed simple website using react and linters

Link https://github.com/belaymit?tab=repositories

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Teaching Skills Following graduation, I worked as an Assistant Lecturer in the Department of Computer Science at Haramaya University, where I taught courses such as Fundamentals of Database Systems, Advanced Database Systems, Introduction to Computer Applications, Computer Graphics, Artificial Intelligence, and Expert Systems, Programming in C++ as well as laboratory courses.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication Skills I earned my BSc degree entirely in English. In the past, I utilized English to present projects and homework in class. When I was pursuing my university degrees, I tutored high school pupils during the summer break. Additionally, I was an assistant lecturer for three years, which greatly enhanced

my communication skills. In addition, I've been enrolled in my MSc program, which is jam-packed with projects and presentations that help me enhance my communication abilities. Moreover, I began the full-stack development course at Microverse by passing fully English-language peer programming and coding tasks. All of this has helped me communicate more effectively.

Interpersonal skills I used to be the team leader for all of the assignments and projects we worked on in class. Conflicts are well handled by me. I have no trouble understanding the feelings of my teammates. I definitely think that team members should be able to communicate easily and I am capable of doing that. A vital component of any organization, in my opinion, is bidirectional feedback. No matter how many people are in the room, I can speak in public with assurance.